<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD Documentation V2.0//EN" "http://forrest.apache.org/dtd/document-v20.dtd">
<!--
COPYRIGHT AND WARRANTY

DingsBums?! A flexible flashcard application written in Java.

Copyright (c)  2004, 2005  Rick Gruber-Riemer (rick@vanosten.net).

Permission is granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document
under the terms of the GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2
or any later version published by the Free Software Foundation;
with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts, and no Back-Cover Texts.
A copy of the license is included in the file COPYING in the section
entitled "GNU Free Documentation License".
-->
<document>
	<header>
		<title>Contribute</title>
	</header>
	<body>
		<section id="introduction">
			<title>Introduction</title>
			<p>The design and implementation of <code>DingsBums?!</code> has been a one man show until now. There are good reasons, why this should change in the future:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>I only have so much time. I work on <code>DingsBums?!</code> in my spare time.</li>
				<li>While I use the application myself, I am not aware of all the features and usage patterns, that real users require. The development of DingsBums?! should be driven what real users need and request.</li>
				<li>My knowledge of foreign languages is limited when it comes to translations of the graphical user interface and the documentation.</li>
			</ul>
		</section>
		<section id="help">
			<title>Where you can help</title>
			<p>The <code>DingsBums?!</code> project is an Open Source volunteer project released under a very liberal <a href="site:licenses">license</a>. There are lots of areas, where <code>DingsBums?!</code> would profit from your help, and where no knowledge of programming is needed: e.g. documenting, proposing ideas, reporting bugs, suggesting bug-fixes, etc ..</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Translations</li>
				<li>Programming</li>
				<li>Accessibility: is the (graphical) user interface usable for people with disabilities?</li>
				<li>Look &amp; Feel: icons, program icon, ...</li>
				<li>Share samples of learning stacks</li>
				<li>Other feedback</li>
				<li>End user distribution: If you happen to have an Apple Macintosh with a recent version of the operating system, you could provide other Mac users with a <code>Mac OS X Application Bundle</code> for easier installation and execution.</li>
				<li>Check need for languages in Middle East (Arabic, Hebrew) and Asia (Japanese, Chinese, Korean, Mongolian).</li>
			</ul>
		</section>
	</body>
</document>
